### **ANUSHILA MAHALANOBIS**

Tel: (832) 900-7150 1950 Eldridge Pkwy Apt 8306 Email: anushilam@gmail.com Houston TX 77077

Objective: A position that enables me to use my in-depth understanding of finance and financial markets

### **Summary of Qualifications**

Financial service professional with more than 6 years of experience. Possess extensive knowledge of complex financial structure and products within debt and capital markets. Strong analytical and problem solving skills. Good interpersonal, organization and communication skills. Personal qualities include adaptability, flexibility, result-oriented attitude, autonomy and strong work ethics.

# Core knowledge and Skill Areas:

- Portfolio Management
- Microsoft Excel
- ◆ Financial Reporting & Analysis
- ◆ Coporate Finance
- Financial Modelling
- Mutual funds
- ◆ Customer Service
- ◆ Compliance
- Financial Forecasting

### **CFA Level I candidate**

# **Professional Experience**

### **Projects Coordinator, Annual fundraiser, Asha for Education**

February 2010 - Present

- Coordinated Work an Hour 2011, the annual fundraiser. Responsibilities included evaluating project proposals from different chapters, coordinating between 73 chapters worldwide to launch and market the event.
- Raised more than \$100,000.
- Accountable for all projects-related documentation and funds disbursement.

## Service Assurance Executive, Birla Sun Life Insurance, Mumbai, India

Jan 2008 - July 2009

- Responsible for ensuring that clients' portfolios are invested in accordance with clients' guidelines and restrictions, internal policies and procedures, and all relevant regulatory requirements.
- Analyzed, resolved and responded to client complaints while maintaining compliance standards.
- Monitored client queries and responses for accuracy, knowledge gaps, and identification of quality needs and issues
- Supervised team members, monitored and guided their activities and reviewed their performance. Provided training and functional support to new recruits.
- Conducted analysis of customer compaints and discrepencies and maintained MIS on a weekly basis.

# Senior Claims Associate, Wipro Itd.

January 2006 - December 2007

- Effectively handled a team of 10 members in the healthcare process environment.
- Analyzed inventory to track productivity figures.
- Trained the team based on the audit reports to ensure that errors are not repeated.
- Effectively managed all reports of production, auditing and quality checks, error database, etc.

# Claims Associate, Wipro Ltd.

September 2005 - December 2006

- Processed claims by reviewing, researching, investigating and adjusting claims
- Analyzed and identified trends and provided reports as necessary.
- Consistently met and exceeded the productivity, accuracy and turn around time standards.
- Assisted team leader in preparing updates for the benefit of the team members.
- Conducted update and training sessions for the team members.

### Sales Associate, Gtl Ltd, India

August 2004- September 2005

- Promoted and sold credit card benefit plans to customers.
- Handled escalated calls in the absence of team leader.
- Generated reports on daily activities and sent them to the supervisor

## **Education**

NARSEE MONJEE INSITUTITE OF MANAGEMENT STUDIES, MUMBAI, INDIA  ${\bf MBA\ Finance\ ,2009}$ 

ANNAMALAI UNIVERSITY, INDIA

Bachelors in Business Administration (BBA), 2007

# **Computer Skills**

Languages: Java, C/C++
Packages: Microsoft Office

Operating System: Windows, Unix, Macintosh

## **Other Certificates and Awards:**

Gold Certificate for completion of the Six Sigma Program.

Gold Certificate for successfully completing the course on "Customer Retention Program"

# **Volunteering Activities:**

Volunteer and project steward, Asha for Education, Houston chapter.

### **Cultural Experience:**

Trained Indian classical dancer. Performed dance programs for charities in schools and colleges and in other social events.